<?xml version='1.0' encoding='ISO-8859-1'?>

<chapter id="chap_01">
  <title>The bpe2 Account</title>
  
  <abstract id="chap_01_abs">
    <para>In this chapter we will introduce the bpe2 account; its directory tree, scope,
      vital folders and programs, what it is supposed to be doing etc...</para>
    <para>The account, is responsible for and should be doing the following:
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><para>Download various GNSS products and data,</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Process GNSS networks on a routine basis,</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Analyze GNSS stations time-series files</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Interact with Ntua's GSAC database</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Upload various information to other servers for presentation.</para></listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para>The account's directory tree and cron table should accomodate all of the above.</para>
    <important>This account is NOT responsible for downloading NTUA's GNSS data (e.g. for the stations 
      installed in Santorini isl.)
      This is usually performed via the gpsdatauser. bpe2 only downloads data (usually rinex) to be processed
      and delets them once the processing is over.
    </important>
    <para>Why is that then? Well, because </para>
    <warning>bpe2 is NOT a data storage account; it is designed to only store data temporarily.</warning>
    <para>So what is this account even there for? lets see...</para>
  </abstract>
  
  <section id="chap_01_01">
    <title>Software Repository</title>
    <para>The bpe2 account is a software repository (well, in technical terms it is not a repository
      since most of the software in this account is actually a clone of some local or remote main
      reposotory). A lot, lot of software resides here, mainly supporting GNSS data (aquisition, processing, etc).
      Parts of this software are base on the directory tree and privileges of this account, so
      <warning>be extra careful when modifying the account's directory tree; there may be software that is
        based on a specific folder structure</warning></para>
    <para>So what software does this account hold? We 'll get to that (see )</para>
  </section>
  
  <section id="chap_01_02">
    <title>Directory Tree</title>
    <para>The directory tree of the bpe2 account, should look approximately like this:
    <screen>
      bpe2@vincenty:~$ pwd; tree -d -L 2
      /home/bpe2
      .
      |-- bern52
      |   |-- BERN52
      |   |-- GPSTEMP
      |   |-- GPSUSER52
      |   `-- unix
      |-- cron
      |-- data
      |   `-- GPSDATA
      |-- gmt-src
      |-- log
      |-- maps
      |-- old
      |   |-- auto52
      |   |-- ntw_euref
      |   |-- ntw_greece
      |   |-- ntw_uranus
      |   |-- src52
      |   `-- unix-geo-tools
      |-- sql
      |-- src
      |   `-- autobpe
      |-- tables
      |   |-- atl
      |   |-- atx
      |   |-- blq
      |   |-- crd
      |   |-- pcv
      |   `-- sta
      |-- templates
      |   `-- dd
      |-- tide-gauge
      |   `-- megi
      |-- tmp
      `-- workflow
      
      34 directories
      </screen>
      Some of the folders are important.
  </para>
  
  <section id="chap_01_02_bern52">
    <title>The <filename>bern52</filename> Folder</title>
    <para>This folder holds the Bernese GNSS Software v5.2 installation and vital scripts.
      <warning>Do not edit files / folders in here unless you realy know what you 're doing!</warning>
      Apart of the installation itself, this folder contains homegrown scripts to assist the routine
      processing of GNSS data. No data should reside here, not even temporary; there is a special directory
      for data, named <filename>data</filename> (obviously!), see <xref linkend="chap_01_02_data"/>.
      </para>
      <para>The folder named <filename>GPSTEMP</filename> contains temporary processing output (ascii).
        It should be cleared from time to time, note however that you should
        <warning>never clear <filename>GPSTEMP</filename> folder when Bernese (or any program ignited by it) is running.</warning>
      </para>
  </section>
  
  <section id="chap_01_02_cron">
    <title>The <filename>cron</filename> Folder</title>
    <para>Wouldn't it be nice if all scheduled jobs and programs could be found in one director? Even 
      as links! That is the purpose of this folder, to host all cron jobs. Add a nice documentation for them
      too. Lets not end up like poor old bpe account.</para>
  </section>
  
  <section id="chap_01_02_data" xreflabel="The data Folder">
    <title>The <filename>data</filename> Folder</title>
    <para>What could this folder do ...?? It holds <emphasis>temporary</emphasis> data! Do not use this
      folder as a temporary storage place. Data and products are saved, erased and edited constantly here,
      so placing important data here is risky. The structure of this folder, going a bit deeper looks like
      this
      <screen>
        bpe2@vincenty:~$ cd data; tree -d -L 3
        .
        `-- GPSDATA
        |-- CAMPAIGN52
        |   |-- EUREF
        |   |-- GREECE
        |   |-- METRICA
        |   |-- SANTORINI
        |   `-- URANUS
        |-- DATAPOOL
        `-- SAVEDISK
        `-- 2013
        
        10 directories
      </screen>
      The folders <filename>GPSDATA</filename>, <filename>CAMPAIGN52</filename> and <filename>DATAPOOL</filename> 
      are used by Bernese. <filename>SAVEDISK</filename> is set-up by Bernese, but we don't actually use it.
      As for <filename>2013</filename>, it shouldn't even be there!
      </para>
  </section>
  
  </section>
  
</chapter>